If you want your AI videos to feel like
they belong on the big screen, you have
to master the light. So, I refined 20
professional prompts to help you achieve
that high-end Hollywood look in every
single frame. So, let's get started. So,
first we have the hero glow in mixed
temperature. The key light is around
5,000 Kelvins from 45° camera left. Then
we have fill light, powerful rim light
at 3K. I'll explain all of that later.
So, this is our hero now. Let's look at
her. You see how the lights are coming
from this side and from this side, and
I'll explain now everything. This is how
could that look like in real life. Now
comes the mood or the Kelvin color
temperature. Basically, Kelvin defines
how light feels. Lower values around 3K
are warm and cinematic like tungsten,
and higher values like 5K are cool and
clean like daylight or blue. So, when
you prompt an AI video model, you're not
just placing the lights, you're telling
it how the scene should feel. So, then
we also have something that I call
dramatic cold night setup. And here we
have the key light at mid higher Kelvins
creating moonlight blue, then casting
shadows on her side, and then we have
also kind of a icy white rim light from
behind. And this is exactly how does
that look like. So, this side here is
completely illuminated by the blue
light. This side is almost completely in
the shadows, and by that AI video model
followed the prompt exactly. Then we
have category two, which I would call
classical face shaping or portraiture.
One of the most famous is butterfly
lighting or the Paramount look. So, this
look is a classic technique where a
single key light is placed directly in
front and slightly above the subject
creating a small symmetrical
butterfly-shaped shadow directly beneath
the nose and emphasizing cheekbones. So,
here is our model.
And now notice something. Look at the
video closely.
And then you will notice that butterfly
effect exactly
here. So, as I mentioned, it is
appearing under the nose and you can see
it like butterfly wings exactly here.
So, this is achieved with the light as I
mentioned previously. And you notice her
cheekbones how emphasized they are. Then
we have the Rembrandt lighting.
Basically, it creates a signature small
triangle of light on the shadowed cheek.
And it is used a lot in dramatic
thrillers and prestige dramas. So, here
is our model. Now, look at this closely.
Okay?
You didn't notice the triangle probably
at the first time, but you'll notice it
now. So, let's stop exactly here. And
here is that famous triangle used a lot
in cinematography. And now it can be
used in AI filmmaking. So, then let's
continue to the category three, which I
would call natural and atmospheric
light. Those are very popular ones. So,
first we have the golden hour, which is
basically called like that because of
the period shortly after the sunrise or
before the sunset when sunlight is
softer, warmer, and rather. Here is our
new model and you can notice what is
happening here exactly.
Yeah.
Sometimes it is enough just to type the
golden hour. Sometimes you need to be
more specific. Then kind of a opposite
of that, we have the blue hour that
creates those twilight mystery. You see,
of course, completely different look
happening here. So, the sun is nowhere
to be seen and those bluish colors
before the night are appearing in our
image creating kind of a mysticism. Then
we have the volumetric or god rays and
those makes the light beams visible
through the air as if shining through
the dust or the fog. It is used a lot in
fantasy, sci-fi, and discovery seen in
ancient ruins, for example. This is the
scene created in VO3 and you notice
those volumetric lightings coming from
above. I also tried the same prompt in
Sora 2 Pro. It worked good, but
something happening with the camera here
on Sora. I don't know what they're doing
here, but you also notice those shining
from above coming here. Of course, we
also need to show the natural moonlight
reflection or the lunar glow, and here
always be careful while prompting not
just to say moonlight because this often
results in a flat blue image. Use the
word specular reflection or skin
moisture, which basically tells the eye
to create that shimmer on the face that
makes it look more realistic. And here
is our guy looking at the sky, and you
see reflection of the moonlight on his
face with pretty much great details. So,
I'm creating all of these videos in
all-in-one AI platform so make AI
because it lets me use many different AI
video and image models in one place.
From VO 3.1 to Sora 2, to Nano Banana
Pro, GPT, Image Z, Image, you name it.
So, if you'd like to try the platform
for free, you'll find the link in the
description down below along with my 10%
discount code. I would call the fourth
category professional studio and color
styles starting with the cyberpunk BI
color neon contrast, which basically
uses two opposing saturated colors
magenta and cyan to light the scene. So,
I created this car in LTX 2 Pro, and you
obviously notice the color grading and
the lightning in this scene exactly as
we prompted. He also created that
lightning scene in VO 3.1 fast, and this
is how it looks like. So, we have this
female warrior illuminated with the
mentioned colors. Then we have the TV
glow or electronic ambience, and this
basically simulates the cool flickering
light of screen reflecting on the
subject. So, here is our close-up, and
you see the reflection in her eyes for
some flickering screen. Then we also
have something called high key or
commercial cleanliness, and this floods
the screen with bright very even light
and removing almost all of the shadows.
And of course, this is used in product
commercials. So, I created this one in
VUE 3.1 fast, and you see there almost
no shadows or no shadows at all behind
the subject, this perfume here. I also
recreated the same scene in Halion 2.3,
and it looks pretty nice. You see no
shadows behind the object. Then
something kind of opposite is rim light
or the halo separation. So, it places a
bright outline around the edges of the
subject to separate it from the
background. So, once again, we have the
perfume bottle. I created this also in
LTX 2 fast, and it looks pretty good.
You see the separation coming exactly
from the borders of this perfume. I
created this also in the C dance, and
here the separation is more obvious and
animated here, but it also looks kind of
a nice to play with the lightning. So,
we're arriving at the category five,
which I would call specialty narrative
techniques. And the famous one is gobo
projection. What it does, it basically
projects a pattern, like for example, a
window blinds onto the scene, and it is
used a lot in crime noir or
psychological thrillers. And here we
have our female detective created in VUE
3.1 fast, and here you see those
patterns behind her creating that
special light scene and kind of a mystic
scene. Most noir films look like that. I
also created the similar in Sora 2, and
here you see those lights and patterns
coming from the Venetian blinds.
Let's look at that one.
And the smoky scenes always needs to
happen in those kind of movies. And I
also created that in Van 2.6 video, and
you see those lights coming in special
degree angle from the window.
Looks also pretty, pretty good, and
pretty nice.
And our female detective is excited.
Then we also have the under lighting or
the villain glow, and basically it
places light below the face casting
shadows upward. And it is used a lot in
horror and villain monologues. So, here
is our character. As first, you see
almost no lighting coming, and of course
we would alight this with, for example,
the match here, and those are those
interesting famous scenes for this
detective. In this category, we could
kind of include also dynamic firework
reflection, which is pretty hard to
achieve for the AI because of the multi
colored light source. So, here is our
struggling hero. He's not happy with the
New Year, and we can see the fireworks
behind and his face changing the colors
depending on the fireworks. Now, this is
a complicated one, and in many cases you
would need to have many different
iterations to really follow your prompt
completely. Here we also have the book
light or the creamiest soft light. So,
we could say that the book light is the
luxury version of a key light, and the
name comes from the physical setup,
which looks like an open book. This kind
of scenario and lightning look like
this.
And it's used a lot in those interview
scenes.
Then we have the negative fill or the
shadow shape. Here is our video. It
looks really, really good. And here's
one tip also. So, if you want your AI
videos to look like a high-budget movies
or simply look better, so you should
stop adding more lights and start taking
light away. So, now we arrived at
category six, which I would call
advanced separation. First, we have the
cameo lightning or the void isolation.
It basically lights the subject
intensely while keeping the background
in total crushed blackness. So, this is
it, and it is obvious that his face is
illuminated and the background is
completely black. Something kind of the
opposite from that is silhouette
lighting or geometric form. It basically
lights only the background leaving the
subject as a pitch-black shape. And this
is how does that look like. It is pretty
nice and interesting way of manipulating
the lighting in AI. Then we have
something what I would call the dual
subject color silhouette or the noir
standoff, for example. Now, as an
environment here I use the photo studio,
so that's why it looks like like this,
but it reminds on the noir film for
sure. And that wraps our guide on AI
lighting. By mastering these 20 prompts,
you now have the tools to dramatically
improve the cinematic quality of your
projects. If you found this tutorial
useful, you definitely want to check out
my other video where I explain 38 camera
moves in AI filmmaking. Combining those
movement techniques with this lighting
will make your AI generations look truly
professionals. If you found this
helpful, please hit the like button and
subscribe for more filmmaking tips.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in
the next one. Bye-bye.